# **Angela Castillo**

Webpage — Email — Google Scholar — LinkedIn

# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a Ph.D. candidate and a researcher at the Center for Research and Formation in Artificial Intelligence under the supervision of Prof. Pablo Arbeláez at Universidad de Los Andes in Bogotá, Colombia. My dedication lies in advancing the field of Generative Artificial Intelligence (Generative AI), focusing on a diverse array of Computer Vision applications within this domain. My research focuses mainly on tackling challenges in image super-resolution, human motion analysis, and enhancing efficiency in text-to-image generation. I am currently working on the intersection between Vision Generation and Large Language Models.

# **EDUCATION**

Ph.D. in Engineering Universidad de los Andes, Colombia

Jan 2020 - Present

Thesis: Generative Artificial Intelligence

M.Sc. in Biomedical Engineering Universidad de los Andes, Colombia

Aug 2018 - Dec 2019

Thesis: Stochastic Video Translation

B.Sc. in Biomedical Engineering Universidad de los Andes, Colombia

Aug 2014 - May 2018

Concentration: Analysis of Biomedical Images and BioSignal Processing

### **PUBLICATIONS**

Adaptive Guidance Universidad de los Andes, Colombia

Dec 2023

Adaptive Guidance: Training-free Acceleration of Conditional Diffusion Models.

<u>Castillo A.</u>\*, Kohler J.\*, Pérez J.C.\*, Pérez J.P., Pumarola A., Ghanem B., Arbeláez P., Thabet A. (2023) In arXiv.

EgoExo4D Universidad de los Andes, Colombia

Nov 2023

Understanding Skilled Human Activity from First- and Third-Person Perspectives.

Kristen Grauman et al. (2024) CVPR 2024.

BoDiffusion Universidad de los Andes, Colombia

Oct 2023

BoDiffusion: Diffusing Sparse Observations for Full-Body Human Motion Synthesis.

<u>Castillo A.</u>\*, Escobar M.\*, Jeanneret G., Pumarola A., Arbeláez P., Thabet A., Sanakoyeu A. (2023) In Conference Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision, Workshops.

SEPAL Universidad de los Andes, Colombia

Oct 2023

SEPAL: Spatial Gene Expression Prediction from Local Graphs.

Mejia G., Cárdenas P., Ruiz D., <u>Castillo A.</u>, Arbeláez P. (2023) In Conference Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision, Workshops.

Guarding the Guardians Universidad de los Andes, Colombia

Oct 2023

Guarding the Guardians: Automated Analysis of Online Child Sexual Abuse.

Puentes J., <u>Castillo A.</u>, Osejo W., Calderón Y., Quintero V., Saldarriaga L., Agudelo D., Arbeláez P. (2023) In Conference Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision, Workshops.

Challenge report ETH Zürich

June 2022

NTIRE 2022 Image Inpainting Challenge: Report.

Romero A., <u>Castillo A.</u>, Abril-Nova J., Timofte R. (2022) NTIRE 2022 Image Inpainting Challenge: Report. In: Conference Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition, Workshops.

Robust Super-Resolution ETH Zürich

Sept 2021

### Generalized Real-World Super-Resolution through Adversarial Robustness.

<u>Castillo A.</u>\*, Escobar M.\*, Pérez J.C., Romero A., Timofte R., Van Gool L., Arbeláez P. (2021) In Conference Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision, Workshops.

#### UltraGAN Universidad de los Andes, Colombia

Oct 2020

#### UltraGAN: Ultrasound Enhancement through Adversarial Generation.

Escobar M.\*, <u>Castillo A.</u>\*, Romero A., Arbeláez P. (2020) In SASHIMI 2020. Lecture Notes in Computer Science.

#### LUCAS Universidad de los Andes, Colombia

Oct 2020

#### LUCAS: LUng CAncer Screening with Multimodal Biomarkers.

Daza L., <u>Castillo A.</u>, Escobar M., Valencia S., Pinzón B., Arbeláez P. (2020) In ML-CDS 2020. Lecture Notes in Computer Science.

### Smart Pooling Universidad de los Andes, Colombia

Jul 2020

### Smart Pooling: AI Powered COVID-19 Testing.

M. Escobar, G. Jeanneret, L. Bravo-Sánchez , <u>A. Castillo</u>, C. Gómez, D. Valderrama, M. F. Roa, J. Martínez, J. Madrid-Wolff , M. Cepeda, M. Guevara-Suarez , O. L. Sarmiento , A. L. Medaglia , M. Forero-Shelton , M. Velasco, J. M. Pedraza-Leal, S. Restrepo, And P. Arbeláez. Scientific reports, 2020

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Graduate Research Assistant Universidad de los Andes, Colombia

Aug 2018 - Present

Algorithm development, empiric validation, and scientific research paper writing, under the supervision of Prof. Pablo Arbeláez.

### Graduate Teaching Assistant Universidad de los Andes, Colombia

Jan 2019 - May 2023

Laboratory assistant of the graduate courses including Computer Vision and Analysis of Biomedical Imaging, under the supervision of Prof. Pablo Arbeláez.

# Ph.D. Research Intern ETH Zürich

Sept 2021 - May 2022

Algorithm development, empiric validation, and scientific research paper writing, under the supervision of Prof. Luc Van Gool.

### Undergraduate Teaching Assistant Universidad de los Andes, Colombia

Jan - May 2018

Laboratory teacher of the undergraduate course: Mathematical Principles in Medicine, under the supervision of Prof. José Ricardo Arteaga.

### **COMMUNITY SERVICE**

Reviewer Officer I have served as a reviewer at CVPR, ECCV, ICCV, MICCAI, and TPAMI

Social Officer at the MICCAI Student Board.

# **AWARDS**

#### CVPR 2022 Outstanding reviewer

May 2022

### Swiss Government Excellence Scholarship ETH Zürich

2021 - 2022

I was selected for a Swiss Government Excellence Scholarship to work under the supervision of Prof. Luc Van Gool, Dr. Radu Timofte and Dr. Andrés Felipe Romero Vergara at the Computer Vision Lab.

### SKILLS

Languages Spanish (native), English (intermediate)

Software Python, PyTorch, Github, Linux, Later, Inventor

<sup>\*</sup> Denotes equal contributions